潮起，天塌
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
零玖/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
presisco
弗莱曼工作室
呈现
沙滩镇不思议出品
沙滩镇，一个沉睡着的海边小镇
Beach City -- a sleepy seaside town.
从远处看，似乎十分平静
From far away, it looks ordinary,
但仔细看，
but take a closer look,
你会注意到其中大有奥妙
and you'll start to notice the cracks in the facade.
背景音乐与U2B著名病毒MV“Never Gonna Give You Up”的前奏相同
我是...
My name is --
呃...
uh...
吾名为罗尔纳多
My name is Ronaldo.
这些年来，我一直在经营名为“沙滩镇不思议”的博客
For years, I've run a blog called "keep Beach City weird."
我的任务：让沙滩镇“不思议”！
My mission -- keep Beach City weird!
以及揭露不为人知的真相
And also to expose the truth.
也许怀孕了？
此处风格影射好莱坞狗仔佩雷斯·希尔顿惯用的网站与图片编辑风格
详见第一季第10集
大多数人选择忽视我的劲爆性揭露
Most people choose to ignore my mind-blowing revelations.
此处布景致敬著名脱口秀《蕨间访谈》
但没人能否认真相
But no one could deny it when the truth
尤其当真相糊了小镇居民一脸时
was pointing right in the town's collective face.
真实影像
外星人入侵！
It's an invasion!
看那玩意！就在那！
Look at that thing! It's right there!
沙滩镇需要被拯救
Beach City needed to be saved.
但威胁是什么？
But from what?
咚-咚-咚
Duhm! Duhm! Duhm!
潮起
天塌
危险
潜藏的
木板路
关于最危险的木板路的真相
KBCW博客倾情制作 纪录片
千万不要学Ronaldo使用的标题字体哦！这种字体在三流剪辑爱好者手里已经用烂了
呃...当时我在为一个大单子洗鱼
Eh, I was just cleaning up some fish for a very big order
法奶奶
当地个体户
突然那发生了
when it happened.
我听到了很奇怪的隆隆声
I felt this very peculiar rumbling,
像这样...
like, "boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom!"
然后突然特别大的一声“BOOM”！
And then a sonic boom!
然后我准备的鱼
And the fish I was preparing
飞到了空中，又掉到了地上
flew up into the air and fell on the ground.
重现
我跑到外面，看见
I ran outside and saw
天上有一个大东西
this great big thing in the sky.
小镇当时正遭受攻击！
The town was under attack!
再说一遍这是什么来着？
What is this for, again?
这是“网家“视频，用于我的博--
It's a web-sclusive for my bl--
哦，呃，对了！那天简直是世界末日
oh. Uh, yes. That day was crazy.
佩迪
薯条店店员
市长说-你害怕吗？
The mayor said --  Were you scared?!
蛤？怎么可能！
What?! No!
我并不-我只是担心
I wasn't -- I was just concerned
商店会发生不太好的事而已
that something bad would happen to the shop.
所以你哭了个惨？
So you cried a lot?
我只能说-无可奉告！
I don't know what you're talking about.
真实影像
快放手啊！
Let it go!
爸爸，不-
Dad, no!
求求你-！
Please, no!
我当时可是承受着巨大的压力呢！
I was under a lot of stress at the time!
噢～嘿
Aww. Hey.
怎么了？
What?
我永远支持你，老弟
I'm here for you, bro.
Mmmm.
我很好！放开我！
I'm fine! Let me go!
这么感人的一幕怎么可能是编的呢！
You can't make up drama this good!
随着一个太空巨掌接近
With the space hand closing in
真实影像
进行第三类接触什么的
for a high-five of the third kind,
Ronaldo的话致敬著名科幻电影《第三类接触》
我们逃离了小镇
we fled the town.
但接着，就像太空巨掌神秘的出现
But then, just as mysteriously as the space hand appeared,
它爆炸成一场爆炸了
it exploded into an explosion.
那蓝色火焰里的是什么？！
What in blue blazes was that?!
看起来是爆炸
I think it was an explosion.
我了个去！
Unbelievable.
我居然没看见！
I missed it!
并没有真实影像
There's no actual footage
展示太空巨掌坠毁在沙滩上，
of the giant hand thing crashing into the beach,
但这里有个重现视频给你
but here's a little re-enactment for you.
Whoooooooooa!
重现
Pfff! Whah!
疼疼疼疼
Ouch. Ouch, ouch, ouch.
啊～我的搜！啊-
Aaah!  My hand! Aah--
沙滩镇得救了
Beach City was saved.
但是谁是幕后英雄？
But by whom?
珊迪
恐怖电影爱好者
女士！-蛤？
Miss! Huh?
你认为是谁拯救了沙滩镇
Who do you think saved Beach City
解决了太空巨掌？
from the giant hand craft?
哦。嘿，罗尔纳多
Oh. Hey, Ronaldo.
等等。这是-你在录像吗？
Wait. A-- are you filming?
请回答问题
Please answer the question.
哦。好吧。呃，当然
Oh. Okay. Um, yeah, sure.
谁拯救了我们？
Who saved us?
呃，好吧，难道不是史蒂文...的家人？
Um, well, wasn't it Steven's...Family?
我-我认为她们不喜欢与人接触
I-I think they pretty much keep to themselves.
史蒂文说她们在保护地球与人类
Steven says they protect the planet and the human race
而且她们有魔力
And that they have magic powers.
这听起来难以置信
It sounds hard to believe,
但我看到过不少疯狂的事
but I've seen some pretty wild stuff.
奇奇
披萨家嗣女
一次，她们为我们做了汉堡包
Once, they made us hamburgers,
我们相处的很愉快
and we were having a pretty good time.
但接着我们遭到一个巨大生物的攻击
But then we were attacked by a huge creature.
嘿！你在拍电影吗？
Hey! You making a movie?
珍妮
令人生畏的小姑娘
哦，别打扰他
Oh, let him be.
这是关于宝石战队的“网录片”
It's a docu-web-umentary about The Crystal Gems.
她们疯！了！
They are c-ra-zy.
她们中的一个还差点打到我脸
One of them tried to knock me in the face.
详见第二季第2集
但我并不生她们的气
I ain't mad, though.
杜威市长，您认为是谁
Mayor Dewey, who do you think
杜威市长
将沙滩市从巨掌下拯救
saved Beach City from the hand craft?
什么？年轻人，我将此归功于选民们
Why, young man, I credit the voters
是他们拯救了沙滩市
with saving Beach City.
我的选民们知道他们任命了
My constituents know they've elected a mayor
可以信赖的市长
whom they can trust to --
啊？不，我是指水晶战士
huh? No, I'm talking about The Crystal Gems.
为-为什么？
W-why?
我在报道一个故事
Well, I'm covering the story.
遮掩？！什么遮掩？！
Cover-up?! What cover-up?!
但，市长-保安！
But, mayor -- security!
嘿！你掩盖不了真相！
H-hey! You can't suppress the truth!
显然，水晶战士背景复杂
Obviously, The Crystal Gems were involved,
甚至与政府最高层有一腿
even at the highest levels of local government.
我决定追根溯源
I decided to go to the source.
现在，我站在-
Right now, I'm standi--
大声点！
Speak up!
现在，我就站在
Right now, I'm standing directly below
水晶战士的城堡下！
the fortress of The Crystal Gems!
我将尝试进行接触
I am now going to attempt to make contact
神秘，隐蔽和-
with the mysterious, reclusive, and --
啊！嗨，罗尔纳多
aah! Hi, Ronaldo.
呃，嗨，佩迪。那是个相机？
Uh, hi, peedee. Is that a camera?
对。我们在做一部影片，关于-
Yeah. We're making a movie about --
这是一部调查报告，纪实摄影
it's an investigative report, shot camera vérité.
酷！
Cool!
那么...想参与惊天大采访吗？
So...Want to participate in a groundbreaking interview?
嗯...
Hmm.
除非你肯...
Only if you...
参与一杯鲜榨柠檬汁！
Participate in a glass of fresh-squeezed lemonade!
噢～。那个巨掌？
Ohhh. That giant hand?
史蒂文
热情的主人
那是一个来抓我们的太空船
It was a spaceship coming to get us.
我们？！我就知道！
Us?! I knew it!
史蒂文，我们知道的太多了！
Steven, we know too much!
不，不是“我们”
No, not us us.
我是指我和水晶战士
I-I meant me and The Crystal Gems.
等等。所以巨掌并不是来抓人
Wait. So the hand wasn't here to snatch up humans
组建人类动物园？
for a human zoo?
Ronaldo立Flag的水平真是超一流啊
或者干预我们有补贴的沙滩市风力电厂？
Or interfere with our subsidized Beach City wind farm?
或者解冻“1%”的冷冻宠物
Or thaw the cryogenically frozen pets of the one percent?!
呃...不，我很确定
Uh... No, I'm pretty sure
它来沙滩市是为了我和水晶战士
it came to Beach City for me and The Crystal Gems.
噢
Oh.
所以如果你和水晶战士不在这
So if you and The Crystal Gems weren't here,
我们就不会被巨掌攻击了？
we wouldn't have been attacked by the giant hand?
噢。肯定不会
Ohh. Definitely not.
当！当！当！
And there it was.
水晶战士并没有拯救我们
The Crystal Gems weren't saving us.
她们令我们处于危险之中
They were putting us in danger.
我感到别无选择
I felt I had no choice
只能赤裸裸地将这丑恶的事实
but to lay bare this ugly truth
展现给不知情的沙滩镇居民
to the unwitting citizens of Beach City.
女士！
:Ma'am!
你知道水晶战士
Are you aware that The Crystal Gems
不仅拯救了小镇
not only saved the town
但同时也是导致入侵的原因？
but also caused the invasion in the first place?
噢。嗯...反正再没有鱼从手里滑掉
Oh. Well, no more fish are getting knocked out of my hands,
所以我没什么好抱怨的
so I'm not complaining.
先生！先生！
Sir! Sir!
洋葱头
？？？？？？
你对水晶战士
How do you feel about The Crystal Gems
吸引危险外星生物袭击的事有什么看法？
attracting an onslaught of dangerous space beings?
你感觉安全吗？
Do you feel safe?
此处洋葱头的举动影射了很多动画节目中寡言角色在规避对话时的举动
嘿！你不可能永远保持沉默！
Hey! You can't keep quiet forever!
你怎么能安然生活，明知我们正遭受
How can you possibly go on, knowing that we are under siege
爸爸
监制人
意图打倒水晶战士的力量的围攻？
by forces meant to destroy The Crystal Gems?
你还有多久完成这个项目？
How close are you to being done with this project?
回答问题，爸爸！
Just answer the question, dad!
我-我觉得挺遭的
I-I guess it's pretty bad.
但像我这样的普通人又能做什么？
But what's a regular guy like me supposed to do about it?
我还有工作要完成
I've got work to do.
而且你也是！放下相机！
And so do you! Put down that camera!
每个人都过于害怕
Everyone was too afraid
意识到他们实际上很害怕
to realize they were actually afraid.
沙滩镇需要一个英雄
Beach City needed a hero.
而且那个英雄必须是我
And that hero would have to be me.
Whoa, whoa --
OK，都准备好了
okay, everything's ready
可以开始我们的夜间潜入活动报道
for our full-on nighttime stealth coverage.
我们这样真的好吗？
Is it really okay for us to be
像这样在这里瞎逛？
lurking around here like this?
我们不是瞎逛！我们在调查！
We're not lurking! We're investigating!
这是见证勇气的时刻
This is a moment of true bravery.
你像我一样勇敢吗？
Are you brave like me?
我足够勇敢到做这件事
I'm so brave to be doing this.
快来！
Come on!
啊啊啊！
Aaah!
Aaaah!
回去，弟弟！
Stay back, little bro!
比比谁先回到危险区
Race you back to the danger zone.
Amethyst的话源自电影《壮志凌云》主题曲
等等！-史蒂文！
Wait up! Steven!
呃，嘿，罗尔纳多。嘿，佩迪
Uh, hey, Ronaldo. Hey, peedee.
你们应该小心-
You guys should be careful --
别开玩笑了！
Cut the pleasantries!
你们都是我们市的危险因素！
You're all a danger to our city!
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
珍珠！现在！
Pearl! Now!
噢，天辣噜！那是个什么鬼东西？！
Hohhh, my gosh! What the heck is that?!
珍珠！现在！
Pearl! Now!
哈！瞄着眼睛！
Ha! Aim for the eye!
好的，石榴
Aye-aye, Garnet.
紫晶在哪？
Where's Amethyst?
在这！
Right here!
让我们完成这个任务吧！
Let's finish the job.
这正是我说的，史蒂文！
This is exactly the kind of thing I'm talking about, Steven!
但水晶战士是来帮助人们的
But The Crystal Gems are here to help people.
但所有的怪物只因为你们
But all the monsters just come here to get you guys
同时四处破坏，让我们处于危险
and then wreck things and put us in danger!
沙滩市如果没有你们会安全很多！
Beach City would be way safer if you guys weren't here!
水晶战士
沙滩市没有他们会更安全
听着 ，薯条仔，
Listen, frybo.
魔法生物确实是被我们吸引过来的
Magic beings are indeed drawn to us,
但我们在沙滩市存在前很久就来了
but we were here long before Beach City even existed.
谁在乎你们呆在这里有多久？！
Who cares how long you've been here?!
无辜的人将一直处于危险之中
Innocent people are in danger
只要你们还在这里！
as long as you're hanging around!
你说的对。我觉得我们还是离开吧。
You're right. I guess we'll just leave, then.
等等？真的？！
Excuse me? Really?!
但，石榴-
But, Garnet --
别但是了，史蒂文
put your buts away, Steven.
我们在这里不受欢迎，那么我们就走呗。
We're not wanted here, so let's just leave.
但，石榴，我们得搬运所有的泡泡
But, Garnet, we'll have to move all the bubbles.
而-而且史蒂文的东西呢？
A-and what about Steven's things?
天！我还挺喜欢这的
Man! Ugh. I kind of liked it here.
呃...
Uh...
任务完成！
Mission accomplished!
呃，你可以把摄像机转向-
Uh, you can turn the camera o--
啊....
ahhhhh.
罗尔纳多
成功的纪录片导演
恩，是的。我做到了。
That's right. I did it.
多亏了我，那些宝石人永远的离开了这个小镇
Thanks to me, the gems are gone forever.
那真是太在了
Mm. That's too bad.
现在已没有可以发博客的内容了
Now you won't have anything to blog about anymore.
拜托，兄弟。我给影片结尾呢
Come on, dude. I'm trying to finish the movie.
好吧，这和你的影片有关
Well, this relates to your movie.
你自己说的
You said it yourself --
宝石人是沙滩镇一切奇特事物的源头
the gems cause all the weird stuff in Beach City,
所以现在他们离开了，也就不会有什么奇怪的东西了。
so now that they're gone, there'll be no more weird stuff.
不
No.
不！
No!
我做了什么？！
What have I done?!
我-做了-什么？
What had I done?
我搞砸了
I done bad.
我犯了一个大错
I made a terrible mistake.
这可是“异死攸关"的大事！
This is a matter of weird and death!
我...不能跑的再快了！
I'm going... As fast as I can!
水晶战士！你们一定要留下来！
Crystal gems! You have to stay!
你们存在导致的每场混乱
Every messed-up consequence of your presence
是我每天起床的理由！
gives me reason to wake up in the morning!
没有你们，我的博客就毁了！
Without you, my blog doesn't stand a chance!
我太晚了！我都做了什么？！
I'm too late! What have I done?!
我让沙滩市...
I've made Beach City...
正常了！
Normal!
我打破了我对小镇的誓言！
I've broken my promise to the city!
还有对我自己的！
And to myself!
你们还在！
You're still here!
求求你别走！我错了！
Please don't leave! I was wrong!
留下来并继续让这个小镇怪异吧！
Stay and keep this town weird!
我完全没有头绪
I had no idea
不知水晶战士会如何回应我的请求
how this Crystal Gem would respond to my plea.
答案你绝对想不到
The answer will shock you.
好吧
Okay.
Haaaaaaaaaaaah!
谢谢！谢谢！谢谢！
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
我熟练的说服宝石人留下来
I had skillfully negotiated for the gems to stay.
也许我以后可以做...
Perhaps I have a future in...
星际外交官？
Intergalactic diplomacy?
最后，
In the end,
我觉得宝石人们确实拯救了沙滩市
I suppose the gems really do save Beach City --
免其毫无异象！
from being not weird!
好了，佩迪，我觉得可以结束了
Okay, peedee, I think that about wraps it up.
拍的不错，兄弟
Good job with the camera, bro.
噢，谢谢
Oh. Thanks.
信息
所有内容均由罗尔纳多制作
佩迪帮助进行摄影
摄影器材为爸爸的相机
剪辑辣鸡
That was very poorly edited.
我们当时真的要离开沙滩市吗？
Were we really gonna leave Beach City?
不。我只想让他把摄像机从我脸上移开
No. I just wanted him to get that camera out of my face.
我在想有多少人看过这个视频
I wonder how many people have seen this thing.
哦。我觉得只有我们
Oh.  I think we're the only ones.
看！
See?
嗯
Hmm.
赞
Click.
整部纪录片的风格与国外九十年代早期“标题党”调查节目（UFO，大脚怪...）类似
视频剪辑特效像是来自WinXP与Vista自带的Windows Movie Maker
如果我可以做到
♪ If I could begin to be
你对我期望的一半
♪ half of what you think of me
我愿意做任何事
♪ I could do about anything
我愿学会像你一样，去爱
♪ I could even learn how to love like you ♪